# 排队站着
Stand in one line
# 鸡蛋 蒜 就这两样 简单吧
Egg and garlic, that’s all, so easy
# 热热乎乎的 鸡蛋加馒头
Warm eggs and Mantou
# 真香
It smells so good
# 山东的家常菜
Homely dish from Shandong
# 咱们把鸡蛋下锅
Put the eggs in the pot
# 鸡蛋煮上了 咱把这算蒜捶了
During boiling eggs, let’s smash the garlics
# 拍一下 这样它不用满处乱跑
Slap to make them more stable
# 咱们如果家里没有蒜臼子
If you don’t have a mortar
# 咱们把它搁到打碎机里头
We could put the garlic into a blender
# 我在家里没有这个
If we don’t have a blender either
# 我们就使擀面杖砸
We could use a rolling pin to punch it
# 其实这个是最好的
Actually this is the best
# 这菜简单啊
This dish is very easy to make
# 小菜当中有智慧
Small dish could also reflect wisdom
# 锅开了 来咱们把馒头蒸上
The water has been boiled, let’s steam some Mantou
# 差不多了
Almost done
# 搁一碗里头 鸡蛋好了
Put them into a bowl; eggs are ready
# 咱们冲一下凉
Let’s cool eggs down with water
# 排队站着
Stand in one line
# 您看 拿凉水激完皮就好剥
Look, it’s easier to peel after cooled down with water
# 先搁这儿
Put them here first
# 这个菜咱们鸡蛋不能煮成溏心儿
We shouldn’t use soft boiled eggs in this dish
# 吃的是沙瓤
We need to make eggs like pulp
# 蒜臼子小点了 把鸡蛋掰碎
The mortar is a bit small, so we firstly break the eggs off with our hands
# 捣一下 先捣蒜后捣蛋
Mash garlics then eggs
# 捣成块状 擓出来
Mash them into small blocks, then take them out
# 其实这捣细了还不好吃 没有口感
Actually it would be less tasty if we mash too much
# 来咱们把这个蒜搁在里边
Let’s put the garlics inside
# 然后咱们
Then we
# （放入）盐
(add) some salt
# 咱们倒入香油
And some sesame oil
# 多搁点
Add more
# 搁上盐搁上香油 这个味儿出来了吧
With salt and sesame oil, the taste begins to show up
# 这小盘漂亮
The small dish is beautiful
# 忙的时候吃干 闲的时候吃稀
Eat dry food when busy, and wet food when idle
# 不闲不忙 干稀搭配
If you are not busy nor idle, you could mix dry and wet food together
# 咱们这馒头也好了
Mantou is eady
# 大白馒头
Big white Mantou
# 咱们来个小薄荷叶
Add some mint leaves
# 当个早点不错啊
A good breakfast
# 是啊 省事儿啊
Yes, very easy
# 先给我大伯来一个 先给师父
Da Bo eat fist. - Give to your master first
# 您看这大馒头
Look at the big white Mantou
# 咱们这馒头咱别切 切的没有掰的香
Don’t cut the Mantou, it’s more delicious to break off with hands
# 来半拉 中间这儿一掰
Take half, break off in the middle
# 你看看 先给你师父 先给大爷
Look, give it to your master first. Give it to Da Ye
# 热乎乎的鸡蛋加馒头
Warm eggs with Mantou
# 怎么样 朝辉  真好吃
How does it taste? Chaohui, very good
# 我第一次吃
It’s my first time to eat this
# 特别香
Very delicious
# 这跟炒鸡蛋完全不是一个味道
Very different taste from Scrambled eggs
# 蒜的辣味不那么呛不吧 不辣不辣
Is the garlic too spicy? Not at all
# 一点都不辣 二伯
Not at all, Er Bai
# 您这好 还没给您照呢您就一大口了
Look, you eat too fast to take a photo
# 这个菜也是我在山东淄博第一次吃到
The first time I ate this dish was in Zibo Shandong
# 后来我就忘不了了
And I can’t forget it since then
# 还有一个东西呢
Missed one thing
# 就这一个薄荷叶让你给抄着了
You took the only mint leaf
# 再来一口
Eat once more
# 正好变了一个味道
A new taste
# 这薄荷 和蒜鸡蛋的清香味 马上变味
The taste was changed immediately, when mixing mint, eggs and garlic together
# 每次吃师父都有创新
Master can always innovate each time
# 这薄荷真香
The mint is so delicious
# 您这吃的跟人家都不一样
You eat very differently from others
# 朝辉 这大礼拜六的 起的晚点儿
Chaohui, wake up later on Saturday
# 捣上两瓣蒜 腾俩馒头 煮俩鸡蛋
Mash 2 pieces of garlic, steam 2 pieces of Mantou, and boil 2 eggs
# 再配碗粥
And a bowl of congee
# 真香
So perfect
# 有网友就一直想让大爷二伯
Some friends want Da Ye and Er Bai
# 讲讲各种淀粉的用途
To talk about the usage of different types of starch
# 再有像我们做松鼠鱼
For instance, when we cook squirrel fish
# 脆皮鱼
Crispy Fish
# 什么焦溜肉片
Jiao Liu Rou Pian
# 还有锅包肉
Guo Bao Rou
# 像这类的
And so on
# 如果要用生粉
If we use starchy flour
# 他炸出来以后
After fried
# 效果还特别好看
The dish will have a good look
# 但是他一挂汁
But after adding sauce
# 麻烦了
The problem comes up
# 吃这有点黏牙
The dish will become sticky
# 不脆
Not crispy anymore
# 炸出来很脆
Initially crispy after frying
# 但是他一挂汁
But after adding sauce
# 瞬间
Immediately
# 他就会回软
It becomes soft
# 吃起来有点黏牙垫牙
And even sticks your teeth
# 但是我们用的白薯粉
But if we use sweet potato starch
# 土豆粉
Potato starch
# 还有玉米淀粉
And cornstarch
# 还有绿豆淀粉
And mung bean starch
# 他炸完了以后是酥脆的
The food is crispy after being fried
# 是吧
Yes
# 所以我们
So when we
# 在用淀粉的时候
Use starch
# 一定要掌握好这几个环节
We must pay attention to these steps
# 如果掌握不好
Otherwise
# 炸出来以后
After frying
# 它效果也不会好
The result wouldn’t be good
# 二伯有什么补充的吗
Er Bai, do you have anything to say
# 大爷
Da Ye
# 非常详细
Very detailed
# 全面
Comprehensive
# 非常勤奋
Very diligent
# 非常详细
Very detailed
# 这是我上
This was
# 大学老师专门给讲的
What I learnt when I was in university
# 淀粉和淀粉之间的
Among different types of starch
# 它的区别
The difference
# 再有一个就是
Another one is
# 生粉在勾芡当中
Starchy flour during adding slurry
# 温度不能太高
The temperature shouldn’t be very high
# 一般你看
In most cases
# 有好多粤菜的师傅
Many chefs of Guangdong cuisine
# 在勾芡的时候
When adding slurry
# 他会把火拉（开） 把锅
They will move the wok away
# 离开火
From the fire
# 在旁边有一个锅架  在90度
Put it on a rack, use 90 degrees
# 左右的温度上
Or so temperature
# 勾芡
Add slurry
# 如果用高温的方法
If the temperature is too high
# 一勾 就是一坨子
The starch will form solid
# 大爷说的这个
What Da Ye said
# 特别关键
Is very important
# 你比如说过去说打蚝油芡
For example, long time ago, when mixing starch with oyster sauce
# 是吧
Yes
# 打蚝油汁
Mix with oyster sauce
# 那火似开非开的时候
When the water seems to be boiled but is not boiled yet
# 然后他还不能大火晃荡
You should keep the temperature not too high
# 是吧
yes
# 然后最后打完以后
Finally
# 最后它封油的时候
In the encapsulation oil step
# 你看封油之后
Then you will find
# 他用勺底下抹着封油
They encapsulate oil using the bottom of fry spoon
# 所以说这就是生粉的作用
So this is the effect of starch flour
# 是吧
Yes
# 谢谢
Thanks